export const questionData = [
    {
        question: "Multiple individuals of the same species form?",
        options: ["populations", "emergent properties", "biosphere", "communities"],
        answer: "populations"
    },
{
        question: "Which of the following statements is false?",
        options: ["Two of three domains contains eukaryotic organism.", "All of them are the correct statements", "When medical researchers test the effectiveness of a new drug, they typically compare the new drug to a placebo.", "For a scientist study to be considered valid, the researchers usually conduct experiments or carefully observe the the natural world"],
        answer: "Two of three domains contains eukaryotic organism."
},
{
        question: '"Your kidneys regulate the water balance in your body”This example indicates that ______ is the characteristic of life?',
        options: ["evolution", "homeostasis", "energy use", "organization"],
        answer: "homeostasis"
},
{
        question: "This organism is multicellular and is autotroph. There for, it could be classified as?",
        options: ["Animalia", "Plantae", "Fungi", "Archeae"],
        answer: "Plantae"
},
{
        question: "The sciencetist observed that the COVID-19 virus causes serious illness. mRNA vaccine might be the best vaccine to prevent the illness. Which is the next step in his/her scientific  inquiry ?",
        options: ["Publish", "Draw conclusion", "Ask a question", "Formulate the hypothesis"],
        answer: "Ask a question"
},
{
        question: "In an experiment to test the effect of mRNA vaccine to increase amount of antibody in Thai people, the amount of antibody would be _____?",
        options: ["Control Variable", "placebo", "standardized variable", "dependent variable"],
        answer: "dependent variable"
},
{
        question: "Celulose is an example of ____, whereas triglyceride is a _____?",
        options: ["protein; nucleic acid", "protein; lipid", "lipid; protein", "carbohydrate; lipid"],
        answer: "carbohydrate; lipid"
},
{
        question: "_____are monomers that form polymers called_____?",
        options: ["Nucleotides; nuceloside", "Triglycerides; lipids", "Nucleic acids; nuclotides", "Amino acids; proteins"],
        answer: "Amino acids; proteins"
},
{
        question: "______contribute to the property of water caled ochesion-the tendency of water molocule to stick together?",
        options: ["Hydrogen bond", "Adhesion", "Covalent bond", "Hydrophobic"],
        answer: "Hydrogen bond"
},
{
        question: "The least inclusive level of classification is?",
        options: ["species", "order", "genus", "family"],
        answer: "species"
},
{
        question: "Which of the foilowing is formed by the linking of two amino acids?",
        options: ["an ionic bond", "a peptide bond", "a functional group", "a glycosidic bond"],
        answer: "a peptide bond"
},
{
        question: "The energy stored in the carbon-carbon bonds of glucose is an example of______energy?",
        options: ["heat", "mechanical", "kinetic", "potential"],
        answer: "potential"
},
{
        question: "Which is the folowing is not the function of lipid?",
        options: ["Body heat procervation", "Component in cell membrane", "Genetic inheritance", "Energy storage"],
        answer: "Genetic inheritance"
},
{
        question: "Which is the folowing sentence is incorrect regarding to energy?",
        options: ["Energy transformation aren't 100% efficient.", "The entropy of the univorse is decroasing", "Energy cannot be croatod or destroyod.", "Heat energy is disordered"],
        answer: "The entropy of the univorse is decroasing"
},
{
        question: "Building carbohydrates _____ energy; ATP synthesis _____ energy?",
        options: ["release; requires", "release; releases", " requires; releases", "require; requires"],
        answer: "require; requires"
},
{
        question: "Which of the following is correct regarding to ATP??",
        options: ["All of them are correct regarding to ATP.", "It is recycled using ADP and the phosphate.", "It can donate phosphate to change shape of the target molecules.", "It is the energy currency within cell."],
        answer: "All of them are correct regarding to ATP."
},
{
        question: "Which of the following is incorrect regarding to enzyme??",
        options: ["Catalase change hydrogen peroxide to water and hydrogen gas", "Enzymes reduce the amount of activation energy required for the reactant to activate.", "pH, salt concentration and temperature have offoct on onzymatic activity", "All of them are correct regarding to enzyme"],
        answer: "Catalase change hydrogen peroxide to water and hydrogen gas"
},
{
        question: "Imagine that you place a drop of red food coloring in a glass of water. The red color eventually spreads throughout the water. This example lustrated?",
        options: ["the active transport", "simple diffusion", "endocytosis", "hydrocytosis"],
        answer: "simple diffusion"
},
{
        question: "The amount of potassium ion concentration in the ceil is higher than that in the neighboring environment. Potassium ion could diffuse into the call through a/an?",
        options: ["osmosis", "active transport", "endcytosis", "facilitated diffusion"],
        answer: "active transport"
},
{
        question: "Neurotransmitter is stored inside the small sacs called synaptic vesicles, and is released into the synaptic cleft of the synapse when a vesicle fuses with the cell membrane. This process, which is known as _________________",
        options: ["exocytosis", "osmosis", "facilitated diffusion", "simple diffusion"],
        answer: "exocytosis"
},
{
        question: "In glycolysis. . . is oxidized and .... ... Is reduced.?",
        options: ["glucose, NAD+", "glucose, oxygen", "NAD+, glucose", "ATP ,ADP"],
        answer: "glucose, NAD+"
},
{
        question: "If the following reaction occurred, which compound would be oxidized? Which compound would be reduced? C4H6O4 + FAD ----> C4H404 + FADH2",
        options: ["C4H4O4, FADH2", "C4H4O4, C4H6O4", "FAD, C4H6O4", "C4H6O4 ,FAD"],
        answer: "C4H6O4 ,FAD"
},
{
        question: "What is the primary purpose of fermentation in cells?",
        options: ["To restore NAD+", "To restore glucose", "To create athanol", "To create ATP in the absence of oxygen"],
        answer: "To restore NAD+"
},
{
        question: "Q: How can C4 plant and CAM plant reduce the chance of photorespiration? Answer: Using enzyme _______[1]for _____[2] to produce C4-acid then translocate C4 into mitochondria to release the CO2, in mitochondria",
        options: ["PEPCase/PEP carboxylase [1], primary carboxylation [2]", "Pyruvate dehydrogenate [1], primary decarboxylation [2]", "Pyruvate dehydroginase [1], secondary decarboxylation [2]", "PEPCase/PEP carboxylase [1], secondary carboxylation [2]"],
        answer: "PEPCase/PEP carboxylase [1], primary carboxylation [2]"
},
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is correct regarding to "microscope"?',
        options: ["Electron microscopes use visible light/laser for source of irradiation.", "Compound microscopes generate color images of living cells.", "Total magnification power from electron microscope is lower than that of light microscope.", "Electron microscope generate color images of living cells."],
        answer: "Compound microscopes generate color images of living cells."
      },
    {
        question: 'Function of Rough ER is to ____________________.',
        options: ["synthesize secretory protein", "break down cellular debris", "generate ATP", "use sunlight to produce food for the cell"],
        answer: "synthesize secretory protein"
      },
    {
        question: 'The light reactions and the carbon reactions are connected by the participation of which molecules? (A) ATP and ADP (B) Water (C) NADPH and NADP+',
        options: ["A, B and C", "B and C", "A and C", "A and B"],
        answer: "A and C"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following structure is described by fluid mosaic model?',
        options: ["Actin filaments", "Nucleus", "Plasma membrane", "Mitochondria"],
        answer: "Plasma membrane"
      },
    {
        question: 'Why is cell cycle control so important?',
        options: ["None of them is correct.", "Because they ensure that metaphase always follows anaphase.", "Because they determine how quickly a cell's DNA get copied.", "Because they help prevent cells with damaged DNA from dividing"],
        answer: "Because they help prevent cells with damaged DNA from dividing"
      },
    {
        question: 'Where does the light reaction take place?',
        options: ["Lumen","Stroma","Thylakoid membrane","Cristea"],
        answer: "Thylakoid membrane"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which is the following is the importance of apoptosis?',
        options: ["It specify the protien production in the cells","It provides continuous supply of replacement","It involves during the development of multicellular organism","It provides addition copy of DNA molecule"],
        answer: "It involves during the development of multicellular organism"
      },
    {
        question: 'Synthesized proteins are usually modified at ____________________.',
        options: ["lysosome", "golgi apparatus","smooth ER","peroxisome"],
        answer: "golgi apparatus"
      },
    {
        question: 'A mosquito cell that is about to begin meiosis has six chromosomes. How many chromosomes does each daughter cell have during metaphase II?',
        options: ["Four", "Six","Three","Twelve"],
        answer: "Three"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is absent in animal cell and is present in plant cell?',
        options: ["peroxisome", "mitochondria","nucleoid","chloroplast"],
        answer: "chloroplast"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following phase of cell cycles involved with DNA replication?',
        options: ["telophase", "cytokinesis","G2 phase","S phase "],
        answer: "S phase "
      },
    {
        question: '_____________________ is a very powerful tool for seeing internal cell structures with high resolution 2D image.',
        options: ["Scanning electron microscope", "Transmission electron microscope","Confocal microscope","Stereo microscope"],
        answer: "Transmission electron microscope "
      },
    {
        question: 'The intermembrane space of mitochondria has a large concentration of',
        options: ["hydrogen ions", "oxygen","FADH₂","NAD+"],
        answer: "hydrogen ions"
      },
    {
        question: '_____________ is produced from nucleolus and sent out from a nucleus to cytoplasm through _____________',
        options: ["Vesicles; nuclear pore", "Ribosome, vesicle","Lysosome, nuclear pore","Ribosome, nuclear pore"],
        answer: "Ribosome, nuclear pore"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is found on all cells?',
        options: ["Cytoplasm", "Genetic material","All are found in all cells.","Ribosome"],
        answer: "All are found in all cells."
      },
    {
        question: 'Which compound is electron acceptor in electron transport chain during cellular respiration?',
        options: ["FADH₂", "0₂","ATP","Pyruvate"],
        answer: "0₂"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is recognized as the smallest unit of life that can function independently',
        options: ["Organism", "Cell","Population","Ecosystem"],
        answer: "Cell"
      },
    {
        question: 'One property that distinguishes prokaryotes from those in eukaryotes is the absence of _________________.',
        options: ["nucleoid", "fatty acids in cell membrane","cell membrane","membraneous organelles "],
        answer: "nucleoid"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is not the recommended ways to reduce cancer risk?',
        options: ["Avoid UV radiation from sunlight", "Eat more fruit and vegetables","Get regular and vigorous excercise","All of them are recommended ways to reduce cancer risk. "],
        answer: "All of them are recommended ways to reduce cancer risk."
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following is not the mechanism that contributes to genetic diversity?',
        options: ["Crossing over", "Cytokinesis","All of them contributes to genetic diversity","Random fertilization"],
        answer: "Cytokinesis"
      },
    {
        question: 'The Calvin cycle reactions can be divided into three main stages: carboxylation, reduction, and regeneration; which stage that did not use ATP?',
        options: ["Carboxylation", "Reduction ","All stages use ATP","Regeneration"],
        answer: "Carboxylation"
      },
    {
        question: 'Which of the following lists the correct order of mitosis stages?',
        options: ["phase, anaphase, metaphase, prophase", "metaphase, telophase, anaphase, prophase ","prophase, anaphase, telophase, metaphase", "prophase, metaphase, anaphase, telophase"],
        answer: "prophase, metaphase, anaphase, telophase"
      },
]

export default questionData